233-New Model Town, Tohana, Distt.-Fatehabad, Haryana-125120 81685-63218, 94651-89863

Email id- kausavkumar23@gmail.com

LinkedIn id- https://www.linkedin.com/in/kausav-kumar

Website: https://kausavkumar.netlify.app



KAUSAV KUMAR

SUMMARY

Hardworking and enthusiastic engineer with more than 3 years of experience in Computer programming and RFID tags. Seeking to enhance my computer and IT skills in Computer programming. Looking forward to be the part of an organization that offers a positive atmosphere to learn and implement new skills and technologies for the betterment of the organization and want to build a long-term career with opportunities for career growth.

SKILLS

- Expert in RFID tags, antennas on AUTOCAD and simulations.
- Proficient in programming on PYTHON/Django/Tkinter, HTML 5, CSS 3, PHP/LARAVEL, MySQL & DBMS, AUTOCAD, JAVASCRIPT, ReactJS, ElectronJS, nodeJS, AngularJS.
- Can also create WORDPRESS, WIX & WEBFLOW websites.
- Good knowledge on writing playbooks on ANSIBLE and cloud computing (AWS, Google Cloud, IBM Cloud) effectively.
- Knowhow of MATLAB in aspects of digital signal processing especially in image signal processing and audio signal processing.
- Studied various operating systems like Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10, Linux lite and UBUNTU.
- Can do programming on HFSS, Microcontroller, Microprocessors & other Digital Signal Processors as well.

WORK HISTORY

FREELANCER, 04/2017 to Current

I am currently working as a freelancer. Designing and developing websites, UX/UI or solving software issues for various freelancing websites as per customer demand is main part of my job. Other than that, Helping college students specializing in DSP (especially in digital image processing & audio signal processing) with their thesis & projects with programming parts of their thesis which require usage of MATLAB. Mainly, executing the results of various research papers & journals (IEEE, Springer etc.) on MATLAB as per individuals demand. For example: "Reducing the noise in audio signals while using Multiple Microphones", "Reduction in memory size of 8-bit JPG Digital Image without Compromising its quality" etc. My recent projects are:

1.) Portfolio Website:

2.) ERP Software:

www.nishtha.info

I created an GUI software for my client using Electron JS

EXECUTIVE ENGINEER, from 02/2019 to 07/2020

PERFECT ID- GHAZIABAD, UP

Worked as an executive engineer. Current project was working on Production Machine PL Light for encoding of various RFID tags

Job responsibilities:

- Designing of various RFID antennas on AUTOCAD
- Testing for RFID Antennas by running simulations on TRAVA or SONET
- Manufacturing of RFID Tags
- Responsible for in-house Server Maintenance and network issues
- Second level support for in house applications based on SQL
- Responsible for trouble shooting of all the issues raised by customer in RFID Tags.
- Maintaining all company softwares & servers.

SKILLED ENGINEER (CONTRACT BASIS), 08/2018 To 11/2018

SHRI BALAJI SECURITY SERVICES (BEL FACTORY)-Panchkula, HR

Verification of Contrast & Length Sensors used in VVPAT Machines

THESIS, 01/2013 To 12/2014

Digital Image Watermarking: Done whole post-graduate thesis on the project for digital image authentication and for securing and detecting any tampering done to the digital image without losing its quality.

INTERNEE ENGINEER, 07/2011 To 12/2011

HPG Systems- Chandigarh, CH

Online pH Meter: Studied, designed and programmed (Microcontroller) various pH meters for chemical and food industries to measure pH of various liquids running through their pipes during six months training period.

INTERNEE ENGINEER, 06/2010 To 07/2010

CROMPTON Greaves- Malanpur, MP

Auto-Transformers: Designing of Industrial grade Step-up auto-transformers in two months internship.

INTERNSHIP, 06/2009 To 07/2009

R.A.K.S.H.A NGO- Jaipur, Rajsthan

Wild Animals and Environment Protection: Still working with this NGO for the betterment of earth environment.

Page | 2 Kausav Kumar

EDUCATION

M. TECH.:: ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING, 2015

Lovely Professional University- Phagwara, PB

- Majored in Digital Signal Processing
- Dissertation: Image Securing & Tempering Deduction
- Graduated with 7.32 CGPA

B. TECH.:: ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING, 2012

ICFAI University- Dehradun, UK

• Graduated with 6.59 CGPA

PUBLICATION

ISSN: 2230-9926: "An Improved Watermarking Technique For Image Authentication", Indian Journal Of Science And Technology, ICICS (IEEE) (December 2016).

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Active listening
- Comprehensive problem-solving abilities.
- Verbal and written communication skills.
- Willingness to learn, team facilitator and hard worker.

ACHIEVEMENTS & EXTRA CURRICULAR

- Organized various events like annual day, technical festivals etc. during School and college.
- Participated in Table Tennis & Cricket competitions.
- Participated in district level archery championship (30 meters) for 15-18 age groups in school time.
- Earned a certificate of merit from Ch. Devilal Scientific Library during 10th All Haryana State Level Science Compitition-2003.

HOBBIES

- Listening music
- Playing Cricket & Table Tennis
- Reading Novels especially Fantasy Novels and Wuxia

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Page | 3 Kausav Kumar